Hello everyone and welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco. My name is
Katherine and we're on the road today.
We're traveling a little bit. That's right
today. We have a lesson that was requested
by one of our users and I think it's a
very handy lesson if we're traveling.
We are buying tickets at a train station.
That's right. So I personally love
traveling by train. I think it's a very
romantic way to see different countries,
different places. We're going to learn
all about how to get tickets and how to
talk about different parts of a train. So
let's first listen to our dialogue.
Hi, I would like to purchase a one-way
ticket to Brussels, please. Certainly, sir.
This is our train schedule. We have an
express train departing every morning and
an overnight train that departs at 9 p.m.
How long does it take to get there?
About 12 hours. We currently have tickets
available only for first class on the
express train. If you'd like, you can
choose a sleeper on the overnight train,
which is a bit less expensive. Yeah, I
think that's the best option. Do you
serve food on a train? 12 hours is such
a long time. Yes, of course. There is a
dining car towards the end of the
train where they serve meals at all times.
We do provide complimentary water and
coffee for all of our passengers. Great.
I'll take it. Here you are, sir. Your train
leaves from platform number nine at
nine on the dot. Remember to be here at
least 30 minutes before your schedule to
part your time. Or else
you might miss your train. I
understand. Thank you
very much. Have a great trip.
All right, we're back. So now we're
going to take a look at a couple of words
that we've picked out for
you on language takeaway.
Language takeaway. So there are many
different kinds of tickets you can purchase.
You can buy for your train
journey. The first time we're going to
talk about is maybe the fastest. This
is called an express train. That's right.
So as the name says, it's an express
train. That means it's a very fast train.
And it depends because in different
places, sometimes they call it the
fast train, sometimes they call it
the in express train. But basically, the
idea is that it's a very fast train.
And it's fast, usually, because it stops
very few times. For example, if we
want to go on the Paris to Berlin train, it
won't stop in every single town. It will
probably only stop a couple of times.
Exactly. So apart from the express
trains that usually they they'll go
in the day time, we have an overnight
train overnight trains are very fun.
Or at least they can be fun if you have
a comfortable place to sleep. Basically,
the idea is you get on the train at
night and you sleep on the train and you
get off in the morning. That's right.
It's actually a very popular way of
traveling, especially if you're on a
budget, because well, you're basically
saving yourself one night of spending the
night at a hotel. That's right. So you're
going to have to find a place to sleep.
If you're taking the overnight train,
there are usually different options.
The most uncomfortable is usually a seat,
like a hard seat. But there are oftentimes
special cars on a train where you
can sleep for these overnight trips.
What are those called? That's right.
And those are called a sleeper, sleeper
cars or you choose a sleeper seat. Right.
So that's pretty easy to remember.
Sleep sleeper. The sleeper seats are the
seats that fold back like you're lying
down. But of course, most places like
China and India and Vietnam, for example,
have actual cars that have beds in them.
Right. Right. Yeah. So you can, as the
name says, you can actually sleep on
this train. Now, if you're going to
buy tickets, you're not going to find a
sleeper train on an express train or a
train that travels during the day, these
are only available at night, usually.
That's right. So sleeper car is what you
want to look for if
you're traveling overnight.
And in those cases, you
oftentimes get hungry.
You need to eat. So where do you
go to eat? That's right. We're going to
look for the dining car on the train. Okay.
So think about the word dining room.
Dining room dining car. This means the
place where you eat. That's right. So we're
going to look for a dining car. And it's
usually in the front of the train, I think,
and you can just go and get a quick
meal over there. That's right. Dining car.
And finally, we have another very important
word here. It's all about getting on and
off the train. So where do you do that?
Well, you go to the platform. The specific
platform where your train is leaving.
So in this case, this guy has to go to
platform number nine. Okay. So usually
that means that there is a cement or a
stone block where you stand. The
train comes to the station. People get off.
You get on. So the place where that
all happens is the platform. That's right.
So it's a remember that in airplanes
or in airports, usually you look for
a terminal for train stations. You're
looking for a platform. All right. And that
number is going to be very important.
So look at your ticket and find out which
platform your train will be arriving
or departing from. That's right. Okay.
So now why don't we review these words?
Let's listen to the dialogue again and
we'll be back in a bit. Hi. I would
like to purchase a one-way ticket to
Brussels, please. Certainly, sir.
This is our train schedule. We have an
express train departing every morning
at an overnight train that departs at nine
PM. How long does it take to get there?
About 12 hours. We currently have tickets
available only for first class on the
express train. If you'd like, you can
choose a sleeper on the overnight train,
which is a bit less expensive. Yeah, I
think that's the best option. Do you
serve food on a train? 12 hours is such a
long time. Yes. Of course, there is a
dining car towards the end of the train
where they serve meals at all times.
We do provide complimentary water and
coffee for all of our passengers.
Great. I'll take it. Here you are, sir.
Your train leaves from platform number nine
at nine on the dot. Remember to be here
at least 30 minutes before your scheduled
departure time or else you might miss
your train. I understand. Thank you very
much. Have a great trip. Okay. So we've
got some really great phrases today
on fancy builder. Not that many of them,
but they're very useful. The first one
is a kind of ticket you can buy. That's
right. We're looking for a one-way ticket
to Brussels. Okay. So a one-way ticket
means that you go to Brussels, but you
don't come home. Maybe you have a flight
later or you have a car waiting for you.
You don't need a return ticket on that
train. One-way ticket is the opposite
of a round trip ticket. That's right. So
usually, for example, if you live in New
York and you're going on vacation, you're
gonna buy a round trip ticket because
you need to go back to your city. But in
this case, we're getting a one-way ticket.
So we're just buying a ticket that'll
only take us there. It's not gonna
bring us back. Okay. One-way ticket.
And after that, we
have a good question.
This is something we can
ask in many, many different
situations. Here, the person buying a
ticket wants to know, how long does it take
to get there? He's talking about Brussels.
That's right. So let's take a look at
this structure. We can say, "How long
does it take two?" And then we can add
another verb there. So for example,
we want to note the amount of time it is
going to require. For example, here we
are asking, "How long does it take to get
there?" In this case, to Brussels. We are
asking how much time is needed to go to
Brussels. But what if we changed the
last part? Well, there's anything. We could
say anything here. We could say, "How
long does it take to bake a pizza?" Or, for
example, Marco, "How long does it take
for you to do your hair in the morning?
" Like, 20 seconds. Not very long. Not very
long. You could even change the name of
the place you're going to. So, "How long
does it take to get to Beijing?" Exactly.
So, just remember this structure when
you want to ask the amount of time needed.
Of course, there are other ways. And
sometimes it's very common to make
a little bit of mistakes saying, "How much
time to Beijing?" Or, "How many hours?
" We don't really
say that in English.
We say, "How much
time?" So, "How much time?
" "Does it take?" All right. And what
about when the person that's selling
the tickets said,
"Okay, the train leaves
from platform number
nine at nine on the dot.
" Okay. So, I'm not really sure where this
idea of a dot comes from, but I think it
has to do with clocks. So, basically, when
you look at a clock and all the sudden,
the hand comes to
12. So, it's nine o'clock.
The hand is on the
12. That is on the
dot. That means exactly. Okay. So, the
train is leaving at 9000, not 930, not 915.
It's leaving exactly at 9 o'clock. So, we
can also say this in normal speech when
we're talking to our friends. I could say,
"Marko, we're going to leave at six on the
dot." Any later, and we'll miss the movie.
Exactly. So, but when you say on the
diet, you're usually emphasizing that
it leaves promptly. It's not going to be
late, and you're kind of emphasizing a
person to be on time. Yes, please don't be
late because 901, or in my case, 604, these
are not okay because they're too late.
Exactly. So, if I say I'm going to pick
you up at 4 o'clock on the dot, it usually
means I don't really want to wait. So,
please be ready at 4. All right. So, on the
dot. All right. So, now let's
listen to our dialogue for the
last time, and we'll be back
to talk with you a little bit more.
Hi, I would like to purchase a one-way
ticket to Brussels, please. Certainly, sir,
this is our train schedule. We have an
express train departing every morning and
an overnight train that departs at 9
p.m. How long does it take to get there?
About 12 hours. We currently have tickets
available only for first class on the
express train. If you'd like, you can
choose a sleeper on the overnight train,
which is a bit less expensive. Yeah, I
think that's the best option. Do you
serve food on a train? 12 hours is such
a long time. Yes, of course. There is a
dining car towards the end of the
train where they serve meals at all times.
We do provide complimentary water and
coffee for all of our passengers. Great,
I'll take it. Here you are, sir. Your train
leaves from platform number nine at
9 on the dot. Remember to be here at
least 30 minutes before your schedule to
part your time, or else you might miss your
train. I understand. Thank you very much.
Have a great trip.
All right, so you mentioned you really like
to travel on trains. I do. Why is that?
Well, I like that trains are kind of slow.
So when you're, well, many trains are
slow, some trains, as we said, like
express trains are faster. But if you're
traveling in a new place, it's a wonderful
way to see the country because maybe
you're going from one city to another city.
Well, it's nice to see what's in
between cities. And so that's why I like
to be on trains. I actually also really
enjoy taking the overnight trains
because I sometimes get a little bit
uncomfortable if I travel for too long,
for example, in an airplane or a car. So if
I fall asleep and I wake up where I
wanted to go, it's really nice. Well, and I
think it's nice also to be kind of
rolled asleep, you know, well, this leads
by the by the train. Have you had any
like very memorable train experiences?
I'm traveling around. I have met some
interesting people and actually they, you
know, local people. So they start
talking to you and really curious because
obviously you're a foreigner in their
country and try to get to know you and
maybe even give you a little bit of advice.
And if you don't speak the
language, it's even a little bit more
interesting because you're trying to
communicate and you pick up a lot of words.
That's true. I actually heard some
really interesting stories from people
who took the trans Siberian Railway from
Beijing to Moscow. They said, "The more
vodka you drink, the more foreign languages
you speak." I don't know if any of our
users have done that. You guys should
let us know if you have any fun,
train, travel experiences. I know Marcos
certainly has some. I've got some of
my own, so we'll all have to share on our
website, EnglishPod.com.
Right. And if you have any
other questions, we'll see
you guys there. Bye. Bye.